Matthew Stafford

📞 – (585) 690-5034 🚱 – www.acsu.buffalo.edu/ mcstaffo/ 💟 – matthewstafford29@gmail.com

• matt2929 in – matt2929

Software 'DevOps' Associate at Lockheed Martin. Part of a team responsible for the cultivation, deployment, and hosting of modern CI/CD tools. Provide SaaS to other teams to modernize software life-cycle practices. Also, solely responsible for the development of Test Automation tools including Selenium and TestArchitect. Previously spent three years researching smartphone applications for rehabilitative

Education

- College: University at Buffalo (SUNY)
- Major: Computer Science o Enrolled: 2014-2018
- o Degree: Computer Science B.S.
- o GPA: 3.545
- o Relevant Classes: Java Intro I&II, Data Structures, Theory of Computation, Introduction to Machine Learning, Algorithms, Intro to JavaScript, Software Engineering(Agile programming intro), Intro to Cyber Security, Real Time **Embedded Systems**

Work Experience

Lockheed Martin

Space Systems

Software 'DevOps' Engineer

July 2018-Present

- · Research and Develop Rancher infrastructure for scalable on-prem Kubernetes cluster.
- · Configure Jenkins pipelines with Gitlab, static analysis, coverage reports, unit testing, and artifact repositorys.
- · Manage OpenShift templates and developing RHEL based docker images.
- · Research and create automated Selenium unit tests suite.
- · Research, develop, and providing training for TestArchitect based automated testing.

The Embedded Sensing and Computing (ESC) Lab

Student Researcher

University at Buffalo

August 2014-Present

- · Developed a 'Stroke Rehabilitation System' that uses a smartphone, smart watch, and 3-D printed cup. Provides stroke sufferers with a rehabilitation tool that tracks and provides feedback to users during their exercises.
- · Designed the system top down from user interface, to real time data analysis, cloud storage solutions, and large scale data analysis of user data.
- · Developed 'Flappy Breath', an Android application that uses a patient's breathing as a game interface. Designed as a rehabilitation system for sufferers of Chronic Obstructive Pulmonary Disease (COPD).

Summer REU: Security of Mobile Devices and Wireless Networks

New York Institute of Technology

Research Assistant

Summer 2017

- Developed and Authored 'TETRIS: Smartphone-to-Smartphone Screen-Based Visible Light Communication'
- · Responsibilities included developing Android Application, crafting research paper, and data collection.
- · Co-Authored 'Indoor Localization through Visible Light Characterization using Front-Facing Smartphone Camera'

The Fisher-Price Early Childhood Research

University at Buffalo

Student Assistant

September 2016-June 2017

- · Developing an interactive book for children that uses an Android tablet to display pages, play narration, and colorfully animate the story.
- · Tracks child's gaze and touches on tablet's screen.
- · Maps data into a graphical interface for clearer understanding of data.

P Awards

- o UBHack Nights Sponsored by Google 'Best Design' and 'Google's Best Use of Google Cloud API'
- Major League Hacking Season 18 University at Buffalo '1st Place' and 'Best Hack that Improves or Works to Preserve the Environment'
- First place ribbon at CSE 50th Anniversary Celebration presenting 'Stroke Rehab' poster September 30th, 2016 and October 3, 2017

Published Papers

- o 'TETRIS: Smartphone-to-Smartphone Screen-Based Visible Light Communication'
- 'Flappy Breath'
- o 'Indoor localization through visible light characterization using Front-Facing smartphone camera'

Projects

- Smart Coffee Maker
- · Augmented inexpensive coffee maker with temperature, water level, an automatic shutoff sensors
- · Flask-Based web application to display coffee's brewing analytics
- · Twitter enabled activation
- Smartphone Enabled Scheduler
- · Developed smartphone based scheduling application
- · Uses Google's Calendar API, Node.js, Mongo DB, and Java Spring to cross reference user's calendar data.

Technical and Personal skills

- Programming Languages:
- · Proficient: Java, XML, Android Studio Development, Real Time data analysis
- · Familiar: Helm, Rancher, Kubernetes, Ansible, Jenkins, Openstack, AWS S3, AWS Cognito, Python, Git, GitHub, JavaScript, Node.js
- General Skills: History of professional presentations (Poster & Sideshow), Experienced in team based research projects, Actively communicates project to both technical and non-technical clients